I will do a quick presentation of Minbif
which allows you to use IRC to communicate with the real world, the modern world
I don't know if there are many who know IRC, or don't know IRC maybe?
Considering the idleness of the room, I will… (shit)
I will (shit) be fairly short.
IRC is an ancient protocol which (fuck) was created in 88
which… (so, something is advancing automatically… now that's better)
So, it's a procotol which was created in 88 and was used by geeks
on the console, which has no extra features besides chatting in rooms and in private
it is still used mainly by geeks, and is a bit endangered
because the mainstream is turned to instant messaging
multiple protocols were created after the 90s, the most known being MSN, ICQ
facebook, and other kind of crap, which usually require proprietary clients
or similar, and have useless feature for the average bearded man
like webcam, file transfer (it's useless, we have mails, etc.)
so Minbif will allow you to fix this
there already was a similar program, named BitlBee
which is quite well-known, and originated the IRC to IM gateway
from your IRC client, you would be able to communicate with non-geeks
it's a fork of aim, a pretty crappy program
which was rewritten, well splitted, as it's now named pidgin, which you might know of
they forked the code, and they maintained the procotols on their own
as a result, no backports were possible, the support older versions of the protocols
they had issues with MSN recently, or Yahoo!, I don't remember
of course the code is pretty crappy
so, as I said, pidgin splitted its application in parts
pidgin, the GUI, and libpurple, which handles the abstraction of the protocols
it handles more than 15 official protocols and also has unofficcial plugins
that's all I had to say
so to start a project which goal was to have a more up-to-date and wider support of the protocols, it seemed to be a good idea
Minbif was created a year ago from that idea, by using libpurple and being an abstraction to libpurple
it is written in C++ and is now fairly stable, in its 1.0.3 version
the idea is that the IRC client connects to Minbif, which is a fake IRC server
which allows you to add accounts for instant messaging services
and it will be the gateway, translating everything to the IRC protocol
allowing you to stay in your irssi to communicate with these aliens
but that are sometimes necessary for sex or this kind of stuff
so, contacts are represented by IRC users, there are status channels, which start with an ampersand
which are supposed to be local channels in IRC
we can see, considering their voice, if they are away or not
if they are not in the channel they are not connected
unlike BitlBee, you use real IRC commands and do not type in the channel
so /invite, /kick, /ban, /query, all that
I don't really need to explain in detail
I imagine you know IRC a bit, maybe
it also handle discussion channels, like group chats in msn, jabber channels, this kind of stuff
it's useful when you use jabber at your job
besides these the basic concepts, Minbif also has features BitlBee does not have
and that are *killer* features
first, file transfers, to get any kind pictures
it uses DCC, the protocol which is not really in the IRC standard
but is over it, to transfer the files
so, this is supported, it's cool
after, the webcam is also handled over IRC
as you might know, there are no streams other than text that are transmitted through IRC
hence we use DCC CHAT to transmit the stream, and an irssi plugin is necessary to display the webcam
this gives roughly this, in short it uses libcaca for the textual representation
since irssi is a console program
so if you want to communicate via webcam with your niece or something like that
you can use the cacacam, which has a fairly impressive rendering
moreover, I don't know if you are users of linuxfr.org
of the board, which is a bit hidden
which is some sort of chat which uses the website and is not really like IRC
while the access is through the website, there is a XML backend to get the messages and post responses
so some clients were developed aroud it
but for people who want to centralize their communications in irssi for instance
a plugin was writtin for libpurple to do this
you must no be able to see much, well, a bit still
I don't know if you know the principle of the Linuxfr board
where to respond we use the *norloges* (timestamps)
it's handled and puts the name of the stuff
in short, it can enhance your improductivity at work
while staying hidden obviously as it stays in irssi
globally, I have no idea what hour it is, but I'm almost finished
in short, for the features
(excuse me? yes? no? ok.)
so, for the future features, is the handling of contacts
which is in short when you have a jabber and msn account, and the same person on it, you can unite them in a single IRC user
the handling of groups, and real webcam, where the idea would be
to have an irssi plugin to open a window with a non-libcaca rendering
I think that's it
Would you have questions, by chance?
Sorry? Do I fuck (nique)?
Oh, what's my nick? Sorry.
Is it a real question?
OK, that's cool.
So, are there real questions?
Yes?
OTR? What is it?
Oh, yes, indeed. But it's on the IRC client side.
It's not Minbif's job.
There are many aspects, of the GUI or similar, that are delegated to the IRC client
so Minbif does not have to do it.
Also, that's cool because Minbif does not have much to do since it is based on libpurple for the protocols
and the IRC client for the display.
It's a cool project because there is not much to do, but allows me to do conferences.
Another question? It would seem not.
Well, thanks.